She has the power to set objects on fire with just one glance!
Firestarter is a horror, science fiction, thriller
film directed by Mark L. Lester.
Charlene "Charlie" McGee has the amazing ability
to start fires with just a glance.
Can her psychic power and the love of her father save her from the
threatening government agency which wants to destroy her?
Andrew McGee, played by David Keith.
Charlie McGee, played by Drew Barrymore.
Dr. Joseph Wanless, played by Freddie Jones.
Vicky McGee, played by Heather Locklear.
Captain Hollister, played by Martin Sheen.
John Rainbird, played by George C. Scott.
Firestarter is a 1984 American science fiction thriller horror film
based on Stephen King's 1980 novel of the same name.
The plot concerns a girl who develops pyrokinesis and the secret
government agency known as The Shop which seeks to control her.
The film was directed by Mark L.
Lester, and stars David Keith, Drew Barrymore, Martin Sheen and George C.
Firestarter was shot in and around Wilmington, Chimney
Rock, and Lake Lure, North Carolina.
This is the second film which featured the collaboration
between Scott and Sheen, after 1972's film Rage.
A miniseries follow-up to the film, Firestarter: Rekindled, was released in 2002 on the Sci-Fi Channel and a
remake, also titled Firestarter and produced by Blumhouse Productions, was released on May 13, 2022.
The film explores themes of fire, based on novel or
book, telepathy, psychic power, girl power.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.